grammarcheck.net 2018-11-26

# Privacy Policy

This privacy policy sets out how GrammarCheck uses and protects any information that you give GrammarCheck when you use this website.

GrammarCheck has always been committed to maintaining the accuracy, confidentiality, and security of your personal and corporate information. We have established Privacy Principles to govern our use of customer information.

We are committed to protecting your privacy and personal data. Therefore, we use your personal data strictly within the legal limits of the applicable data protection laws. With this privacy policy, we inform you of the personal data we collect when you use our services.

In the following, we inform you about the type, scope, and purposes of the collection and use of personal data. You can access this information at any time on our website, [www.grammarcheck.net](https://www.grammarcheck.net/).

## 1\. Data controller/Contact

The data controller responsible for data processing within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation, other data protection laws in force in the Member States of the European Union, and other provisions of a data protection nature is:

GrammarCheck  
c/o Roth Media GmbH (Swiss Limited Liability Company)  
Lorrainestrasse 19  
3013 Bern  
Switzerland

Please feel free to address any questions or concerns regarding data protection or privacy to privacy(at)grammarcheck.net.

## 2\. Scope of data protection

Data protection concerns personal data as defined in the General Data Protection Regulation, i.e. all information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. Identifiable is any natural person who can be identified directly or indirectly, in particular by assignment to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier, or one or more special characteristics. Usage data is data required to use our website; this data includes the start, end, and extent of the user’s website use.

## 3\. Automatic data collection via website access

When you access our website, your device automatically transmits certain data for technical reasons. The following data is stored separately from any other data you may transmit to us:

  * Date and time of access
  * Browser type and version
  * Operating system
  * URL of the website visited prior to ours
  * Amount of data sent
  * Requesting domain
  * Notification of successful data retrieval
  * Search term when using a web browser
  * IP address

This data is stored for purely technical reasons and is never associated with any particular individual. The data about website access is used for error and performance analysis, ensuring the security of the systems, and to improve our grammar checker.

## 4\. Texts and corrections — Grammar Checker (free)

Please note that you may not use our online grammar checker for any texts containing personal data of any kind.

If you use our grammar checker, you transfer to our servers all texts you would like to check. This is required for us to perform the correction and to provide you with service. We do not store your texts and the corrections, nor do we keep records of any text that you enter on our website.

## 5\. Texts and corrections — Grammar Checker (deep)

When using Grammar Checker (deep), the texts you submit are being transferred to a third party service. If you sign up to their service, you’ll have to consent to their privacy policy. We cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites (third party) and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement and terms of service applicable to the website in question.

Please note that you may not use our grammar check service for any texts containing personal data of any kind.

## 6\. Newsletter

When signing up to our free newsletter, the following personal information is stored and processed by a third party (“GetResponse”) newsletter service provider:

  * Email address
  * Your name (First name, last name, or both)
  * Your IP address
  * Your location

In order to process emails, we pass on the data to the newsletter service provider commissioned by us:

GetResponse Sp. z o.o. (Polish Limited Liability Company)  
Arkońska 6, A3  
80-387 Gdańsk  
Poland

You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time, by clicking on the _Unsubscribe_ link at the bottom of one of our emails.

## 7\. Cookies

We use “cookies” to provide you with a wide range of functionalities and enhance your user experience. Cookies are tiny files stored on your computer through your browser. If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may deactivate cookie storage on your computer by changing your browser settings accordingly. Please note that the proper functioning of the website may be impaired and the range of functionalities may be limited if you deactivate cookies.

In particular, we are using the following cookies:

  * Cookies with an individual identifier to re-identify your browser  
(please refer to the “Google Analytics” sections for further details)

## 8\. Google Analytics (with anonymization function)

We use Google Analytics (with anonymization function), a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies which permit an analysis of your use of the website. The information about your website use generated by the cookie (including your truncated IP address) is transmitted to a server controlled by Google in the USA and is stored there. Google uses this information to analyze your use of the website, to generate reports about website activities for website operators, and to provide further services related to website and internet use. Google may also share such information with third parties to the extent it is legally required to do so and/or to the extent third parties process data on behalf of Google.

You can find detailed information about how Google uses your data in [Google’s privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

We use Google Analytics with the anonymization function. By means of this addition, Google shortens and anonymizes the IP address of the Internet connection of the person concerned, if our Internet pages are accessed from a member state of the European Union or from another state party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area.

You may deactivate Google Analytics with the help of a browser add-on if you do not want this website analysis.

User-based event data at Google Analytics is deleted after 50 months.

## 9\. Your rights

You have the following rights under European Union law. If you wish to exercise any of the rights below, simply write to us at the above address.

  * Right to confirmation and right to information – we will be happy to confirm whether we process your personal data, what data it is and for what purpose it is processed.
  * Right to rectification – if the data we store is incorrect, we will of course be happy to correct it.
  * Right of erasure – if you want your personal data to be deleted, we will, as far as legally possible, comply with your request. If data must be kept for legal reasons, it will be blocked. The data is then no longer available for further use.
  * Right to restriction of processing – should you wish to restrict use, we will, as far as legally possible, comply with your request.
  * Right to object – if you wish to object to any consents already given, we will pursue your request accordingly.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint to a supervisory authority about the processing of your personal data.

## 10\. Security

We are committed to ensuring that our servers are secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure any data that you enter into our website.

## 11\. Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## 12\. California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.

## 13\. Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

## 14\. Online Privacy Policy Only

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.

## 15\. Your Consent

By using our site, you consent to our privacy policy.

## 16\. Changes to privacy policy

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy. The current version of the privacy policy is always accessible [here](https://www.grammarcheck.net/privacy-policy/).

Last updated: 25 May 2018
